翻译   鱼小姐啦
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   肉松富士
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   某羽
翻译   somehacker
翻译   小饭
时间轴   兜兜兜爹
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
特效   草草
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第四集
服从行政命令不能为
Deference to the executive cannot possibly justify
默罕默德先生及其家属的死伤辩解
the injuries to Mr. Mahmoud or the death of his family members.
如果不裁定这是错误的
If you do not say that this is wrong,
这是违反宪法的
that this is unconstitutional,
那我们也无法防止
there is nothing to prevent this
类似无意义的惨剧再次发生
sort of senseless tragedy from happening again.
我们要求的不过是改革和监督
We ask for nothing more than reform and oversight.
您的裁决将成为关键的第一步
Your ruling is a crucial first step.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你  凯特伊奥先生
Thank you, Mr. Katyal.
邓巴女士
Ms. Dunbar.
首席大法官先生及庭上  请容我说明
Mr. Chief Justice, and may it please the court,
我国的无人机项目和其他秘密行动
the security of American citizens is the reason our drone program
正是为保护美国公民安全而存在
and other covert operations exist.
但维护安全往往要付出代价
But that security often comes with a cost.
此时此刻  总统正在阿灵顿公墓
At this very moment, the president is at Arlington Cemetery,
下葬三位殒命阿富汗山区的
laying to rest three Navy SEALs
海豹突击队队员
who perished on a mountainside in Afghanistan.
他们献出了自己的生命去拯救他人
They gave their lives to save others.
上帝对亚伯拉罕说"把你的儿子
And God said to Abraham, "Take your son,
亚伯拉罕为《圣经》人物
希伯来民族的创始人
上帝要求他杀子献祭以考验其虔诚
你的独生子  你所爱的以撒
your only son, whom you love, Isaac,
献为燔祭"
and sacrifice him."
亚伯拉罕答应了
Abraham was willing.
但当他在圣坛边举刀对着以撒时
But when he raised his knife above Isaac on the altar,
上帝阻止了他
God stopped him.
因为亚伯拉罕已经证明了他对上帝的虔诚
For Abraham had proven his devotion to God.
上帝为证明他对我们的爱
Then God, to prove his devotion to us,
也做出了牺牲
made his own sacrifice.
"上帝爱世人  甚至将他独子献给他们"
"For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son."
虔诚  牺牲
Devotion. Sacrifice.
爱
Love.
这就是上帝教导我们的
This is what the Lord teaches us.
也是这三位年轻人身体力行的
And what these young men have exemplified.
我们将永远尊敬他们
We shall forever honor them.
在天堂  他们将得永生
And in heaven, they will have eternal life.
阿门
Amen.
预备  拉
Ready, pull.
如您所知  在要求撤诉时
As you are aware, we have invoked the State secrets privilege
我们援引了国家机密特权
during our request for dismissal.
但现在总统授权我
But I have authority from the president
公开一些保密文件
to share some of the classified brief
旨在使政府的辩词更可信
in order to reinforce the government's argument.
你确定要这么做吗  邓巴女士
Are you certain you want to do that, Ms. Dunbar?
是的  首席大法官先生  总统也是
I am, Mr. Chief Justice. And so is the president.
那么政府是公开承认为这次袭击负责了
So the government is publicly admitting responsibility for the strike?
没错  法官阁下
It is, Your Honor.
我们成功定位了恐怖分子祖里·阿齐
The terrorist successfully targeted was Zuri Aziz.
他常常利用平民作为人盾
He routinely used civilians as human shields.
默罕默德先生一家不知与阿齐同处一栋楼
Mr. Mahmoud's family did not know Aziz was in the same building.
无人机袭击该为他们的死亡负责
The drone strike is responsible for their deaths.
默罕默德先生遭受了巨大的伤害和损失
Mr. Mahmoud has suffered a terrible injury and loss.
政府的行动虽造成了悲剧  但并非不合法
While the government's action is tragic, it wasn't unlawful.
这次行动是合法  必需以及正确的
It was legal, it was necessary, and it was right.
希瑟·邓巴  她从没竞选过
Heather Dunbar? She's never run for office.
没有政治觉悟
You don't become Solicitor
是没法当上副检察长的
General without being politically savvy.
当选总统可不只需要觉悟
It takes more than savvy to be elected president.
别忘了
Don't forget,
沃克案调查后她在全国也有点名气了
she has a national profile after the Walker investigation.
真理和正义的化身
Truth and justice personified.
如果领导层想改变党的形象  她...
If the leadership wants to redefine the party, she's--
罗斯·佩罗之后再没有
No one with this little experience
美国商人
曾经于1992年和1996年
两次参加总统竞选
虽然最终败选
但取得历来第三党最多的普选票
经验如此匮乏的强劲竞争者了
has ever been a real contender since Ross Perot,
而且他没经验却有的是钱
and at least he had the money.
她也有钱  她家族拥有邓巴装甲车公司
So does she. Her family owns Dunbar Armored Cars.
有必要的话她能负担得起全部竞选费用
She could finance her entire campaign if she needed to.
但有什么能防止权力滥用呢
But what prevents the abuse of power?
行政机关不能立法  不能接受拨款
The executive can't legislate, can't receive appropriations,
不能判人入监
can't sentence people to imprisonment.
这些都要靠其他机构
All of these depend on the other branches,
保证行政权受控
which keeps executive power in check.
但我们都知道  紧急情况下
But we know for a fact that, in emergencies,
行政机关会考虑采取
the executive will contemplate actions
没有明确法律依据的行为
that do not have clear legislative authority
这可能就会与宪法相违背
and might be constitutionally dubious.
包括
Including--
您是要问无人机袭击吗  法官阁下
Are you asking about drone strikes, Your Honor?
没错  无人机袭击
Yes. Drone strikes.
对行政权失控的恐惧被夸大了
The fear of an out-of-control executive is exaggerated.
由于选举压力和其他政治因素
The president has strong electoral and other political incentives
总统采取行动得考虑公众利益
to act in the public interest.
你本人就曾调查过白宫滥用职权的案件
You yourself have investigated the White House for abuse of power.
最后迫使时任总统辞了职
It forced a president to resign.
而现在你又声称
Now you maintain that, uh,
我们应该给总统一些活动空间
we should give our president a wide berth?
我今天不是想维护某个个人
I am not here to defend any one person,
而是要维护总统体制
but rather the office of the presidency itself.
我们必须让政府里的每一个人按章守法办事
We must hold everyone in government accountable to the law.
但我们不能随意解释法律
But we must not manufacture our interpretation of the law
来侵蚀宪法赋予的权威
to erode constitutional authority.
我们能起诉总统本人  但不能动摇总统体制
We can prosecute presidents, but not the presidency.
我们必须假设这事是真的
We have to assume this is happening.
我们必须在她参选之前就堵死她的路子
We need to end her campaign before it begins.
她履历毫无瑕疵
She's clean.
她就任副检察长时沃克就审查过她
Walker vetted her for Solicitor General,
后任命她为特别检察官时又审过一次
then again when he made her special prosecutor.
正因为这些经历  她才如此受欢迎
That's one of the things that makes her so attractive.
谢谢你  杰姬
Thank you, Jackie.
应该的  先生
Yes, sir.
如果不能踢她出局
Well, if we can't knock her out,
就必须得另想办法
we have to figure out another way.
很震撼  是不是
It's something, isn't it?
是啊
Yes, it is.
美国一贯不支持向中东地区
Traditionally, the United States has not supported
派驻军队
military action in the Middle East.
但若有一支中立的联合国维和部队进驻约旦河谷
But a neutral UN peacekeeping force in the Jordan Valley
将为构建一个可持续的  长期的和平局势
is an essential first step to sustainable,
迈出关键的第一步
long-term peace.
美国将赞成这一决议案
The United States will vote "yes."
谢谢您  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
现在有请俄罗斯联邦的代表进行发言
I give the floor to the representative of the Russian Federation.
俄罗斯也致力于维护地区和平稳定
Russia is also committed to stability in the region.
但让联合国介入如此复杂的局势
But inserting the UN into such a complicated situation
将对实质和平造成无可挽回的损害
could irrevocably damage the hopes of real peace.
我强烈建议我的各位同事
I strongly encourage my colleagues
不要支持此项决议案
to not support this resolution.
谢谢  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
如果没有更多发言请求
With no further requests to speak,
我宣布此决议草案进入表决环节
I put the draft resolution to a vote.
赞成的请举手
All those in favor?
反对的请举手
Those against?
弃权的请举手
Those abstaining?
投票结果  13票赞成  1票反对
The vote is 13 in favor, one against,
1票弃权
one abstention.
此项决议草案未获通过
The draft resolution does not pass
因为有安理会常任理事国投反对票
due to the "No" Vote by a permanent member of the Security Council.
我们原本希望俄罗斯能改变心意
但他们的否决也在意料之中
因此我们需要您协助我们越过安理会
我们不想削弱常任理事国的否决权
我们不会开创这样的危险先例
如果不能取得联大多数赞成  不能推翻否决
以色列仍然支持你们吗
否则我也不会打给您了
那只要以色列支持  我方也赞成
太好了  谢谢您  大使先生
我们决定提交联大投票时会通知您的
伊莉安娜  法国同意了
Ileana, France is in.
我需要确定以色列不会动摇
I need to be certain Israel will stand firm.
以色列不会坚守承诺的
Israel will never maintain its commitment.
以色列和世界上绝大多数国家一样
Israel wants what the rest of the world wants,
都想要长久的安全
sustainable security.
信我一句
Trust me on this,
我在联合国和耶路撒冷打了好多年的交道
I've dealt with Jerusalem for many years at the UN.
一旦局势不利  他们马上就会弃你而去
The moment it gets difficult, they'll turn their back on you.
而局势势必会恶化
And it will get difficult.
你说得对
You're right.
我无法预测未来他们会有什么举动
I can't predict how they will act down the road,
但我知道他们会赞成这项决议案的
but I do know they will vote for this resolution.
拭目以待吧
We'll see.
绕过安理会实在是鲁莽之举
Going around the Security Council is a radical move.
不是鲁莽  是有理有据
It's not radical, it's justified.
你从旧纸堆里翻出60多年前的先例
You dust off some 60-year-old precedent
还觉得是有理有据
and think you're justified?
第377号决议案发动了一场战争
The Uniting for Peace resolution was used to start a war.
那是为了阻止朝鲜的进攻
To end North Korea's aggression.
文字游戏而已
Semantics.
已经有93个国家支持这个决议案
Ninety-three nations on board already,
还包括以色列  这可不是文字游戏
including Israel, that's not semantics.
克莱尔  克里姆林宫给了我很大的压力
Claire, I'm getting a lot of pressure from the Kremlin.
佩特罗夫不想闹到联合国大会上去
Petrov doesn't want this to go to the General Assembly.
再给我点时间说服他
Give me a little more time to work on him.
已经给你一个月了  我们要行动了
We've given you a month. We're moving forward.
什么事
Yes?
邓巴女士来了
Ms. Dunbar is here.
让她进来
Send her in.
古兰经
希瑟
Heather.
总统先生
Mr. President.
我听了你今早辩护的音频
I listened to the audio of your defense this morning.
表现很出色
It was outstanding.
您说得没错  要打感情牌
You were right about making the emotional argument.
我觉得这能让国家伤愈  请坐
I think it will help the country heal. Please, have a seat.
我今晚还准备私下见默罕默德先生
I'm also going to meet later tonight with Mr. Mahmoud privately.
亲自向他道歉
To personally apologize.
这么做很有同情心
That's a compassionate thing to do.
听你辩护时  我还注意到
When I listened to your argument, I also heard something else.
雅各布斯法官曾质询你
There was a moment when Justice Jacobs
无人机袭击的事
was asking you about drone strikes.
是  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
他停顿了...非常久
And he paused... for quite a long time.
我觉得  他只是一时卡壳了
I think... he just lost his train of thought.
好吧
Well...
接下来我说的  一定要保密
What I'm about to tell you has to remain between us.
没问题
Of course.
雅各布斯法官有老年痴呆
Justice Jacobs has Alzheimer's.
几个月前他告诉了我
He came to me a few months ago to tell me.
现在还是早期
Now, it's in the early stages,
除非有意观察  不然发现不了
so you wouldn't even notice unless you know what to look for.
他还想待在法庭上吗
He wants to remain on the court?
我要说的就是这个
Well, that's what I want to discuss.
他想退休
He wanted to retire.
我叫他再多等会儿
I asked him to hold on just a little while longer,
让我先找到合适的人选  现在我找到了
until I could find a suitable replacement and now I have.
我觉得...你最合适
And I want that replacement... to be you.
你意下如何
What do you think?
我...自愧不配  先生
I'm... humbled, sir.
您愿考虑我  我着实震惊
And... honestly surprised that you'd consider me.
为什么
Why is that?
因为以前的纠葛
Given our history.
我说过那些都过去了  就都过去了
When I said that was water under the bridge, I meant it.
你有我国最强的法律头脑
You have the finest legal mind in this country,
对宪法理解很透彻
a deep understanding of the Constitution,
共和党不敢阻止你提名
and the Republicans wouldn't dare block your nomination.
毕竟你检举过民主党的总统
After all, you prosecuted a Democratic president.
当副检察长屈才了
You're too good to be Solicitor General.
你要拿稳这个铁饭碗
Let's make sure you have a job for life.
很感激您这么说  先生
I appreciate you saying that, sir.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
容我再考虑考虑
This is a lot to process.
大选前就要搞定这事
It's important we do this before the election.
共和党人当了总统就没准了
We could end up with a Republican president.
除非你真想坐这个位置
And I don't want to suggest your name to Jacobs
不然我不会向雅各布斯提你的名
unless you truly want the position.
所以...现在就告诉我
So... I need to know now.
好  我非常荣幸
Yes. It would be a great honor.
很好  祝贺你
Good. Congratulations.
你去告诉家人  我去跟雅各布斯说
You speak to your family. I'll speak to Jacobs.
谢谢  总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
带宽使用未授权
注意  您已超过带宽授权限制  需要更高权限
你看到了吗
Did you see this?
看到什么
See what?
我刚收到警告了
I just got an alert.
不知道  我好一阵没见到吉姆了
I don't know. I haven't, uh... seen Jim in a while.
真奇怪
That's weird.
我想向你做出最诚挚的抱歉
I want to offer you my sincerest regret.
希望你能够接受
And I hope that you will accept my apology.
抱歉  我做不到
I'm sorry, but I can't.
我知道应该早点道歉的
I know it should have come sooner.
监督必须更严格
There needs to be more oversight.
有美国国会监督呢
Well, there is congressional oversight.
还有严格的制度来防止附带伤亡
We have a rigorous system to prevent collateral damage.
平民被列为"其他激进分子"
Civilians are listed as "other militants."
但政府并未提供确凿证据
But the government offers no evidence that's true.
反正就我而言是没有
It definitely wasn't in my case.
你们的程序哪里严格了
How rigorous can your process be?
平民死于无人机袭击的数目
The numbers of non-combatants who are being killed by drone strikes
比以往少多了
is lower than it's ever been.
这些数字是假的
Those numbers are false.
2010年只死了一个平民  肯定不对
One civilian killed in 2010? That has to be wrong.
听着  我不认为五角大楼对此说了实话
Look, I don't think the Pentagon is being honest about--
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我去叫医生
I'll get the doctor up here.
不必了  过一会儿就好
Don't do that. It'll pass.
幻痛而已
Phantom pain.
你知道我来时想做什么吗
You know what I dreamed of when I came here?
徒手掐死你
Choking you with my bare hands.
默罕默德先生  你可以恨我
Mr. Mahmoud, you may hate me.
恨我的职位
You may hate the office I hold.
但现实是
But here's the reality:
每天我必须做出我但愿是正确的决定
I must make decisions every day that I hope are just.
我也不能一直明辨是非
I don't know right from wrong all the time.
我倒希望我能
I wish I did.
但我决不能优柔寡断
But what I can't be is indecisive.
《古兰经》中说  "夺一无辜之人性命
It says in the Qur'an: "The taking of one innocent life
如了结全人类之性命"
is like the taking of all mankind."
不过它也说  "救人一命
It also says that "The saving of one life
如保全人类之命"
is like the saving of all mankind."
你把我叫来  不是想跟我道歉
You didn't ask me here to apologize.
而是想让我原谅你
You asked me here to forgive you.
那袭击不是我下的命令
I didn't order the strike that--
我不会原谅你  总统先生
I won't forgive you, Mr. President.
我不想让你夜里能安心入睡
I don't want to make it any easier for you to sleep at night.
知道《古兰经》的只字片语也不能免除你的罪孽
And knowing a few lines of the Qur'an does not absolve you.
我对这个国家负有责任  默罕默德先生
I have a duty to this nation, Mr. Mahmoud.
我发过誓的
I swore an oath.
责任和谋杀之间有道微妙的界线
There's a fine line between duty and murder.
只有你有能力阻止我遭遇的事
Only you have the power to stop what happened to me.
下次你使用这份权力时  希望你能三思
The next time you wield it... I hope you'll think twice.
一定会的  密查姆
Yes, of course. Meechum!
先生  怎么了
Yes, sir?
把默罕默德先生送出去
You show Mr. Mahmoud out.
全国范围内持续两个月的随机抽样
Two months of random sampling across the country.
不到所有可用数据的千分之一
Less than a tenth of a percent of all incoming data.
怎么这么少
Why so little?
你知道我们监视着多少个摄像机吗
You have any idea how many cameras we monitor?
华盛顿所有主机的CPU核心份额
The CPU core quota of every mainframe in Washington
都处理不了全部数据
couldn't handle all that data.
我企图加倍样本范围但是触发了警报
I tried doubling the sample range and it set off alarms.
我就差这么一点被抓
I came this fucking close to getting caught.
我们只能缩小搜索范围
Okay, we just need to narrow the search, man.
要覆盖的范围太广了
It's too much ground to cover.
怎么缩小
How?
我需要更多关于瑞秋的信息
I need more information on Rachel.
她喜欢的书  电影之类的  什么都行
Favorite books, fuckin' movies. Anything.
我一无所知
I don't know.
拜托  她提起过去哪里吗
Come on. Did she ever talk about going anywhere?
去什么地方旅游之类的
Traveling to some place?
没有  她那时不能去旅游
No. Traveling wasn't an option.
我需要更多信息
I need more, man.
那另一个女孩丽萨呢
What about the other girl? Lisa.
我正在看她的电子邮件
I'm reading her e-mails.
并追踪了她的手机  什么也没发现
I'm tracking her phone. There's nothing there.
但我们可以接近她  跟她谈谈
We should get close to her, though. We should talk to her.
问出点有用的东西
Extract something.
她会认出我来的
She might recognize me.
我来吧
I'll do it.
这叫我紧张
That makes me nervous.
社会工程而已  我可以"黑"她的回忆
It's social engineering. I'll just hack her that way.
她一点也不会起疑的
She won't suspect a thing.
如果我们不试点新办法就找不到瑞秋
If we don't try something new, we're not gonna find Rachel.
吃点煮花生吧
Help yourself to some boiled peanuts.
不了  谢谢  盐太多了
No, thank you. Too much salt.
我来这儿的第一周
First week I was here,
我问服务员能不能给我来点煮花生
I asked one of the stewards if I could have some boiled peanuts.
我小的时候经常吃
I used to eat them all the time as a kid,
从那以后的每一天
and I'll be damned if there hasn't been
我都要满满一碗的煮花生
a full bowl of peanuts here every day since.
他们肯定有口昼夜不停煮花生的锅
They must have a pot boiling 'round the clock.
露丝现在让我吃甘蓝脆片
Ruth has me eating kale crisps now.
说对身体好  我受不了那东西
Says they're good for me. I can't stand the things.
我让厨房给剥好了皮
I have them shucked in the kitchen,
这样吃的时候不会弄脏手指
so you don't even have to get your fingers dirty.
随意吃  享受一下生活
Feel free. Live a little.
大法官先生  我们上次谈完后
Mr. Justice, since we last spoke,
我做了很多反省
I've done a lot of soul searching.
我要求你继续做法官  这不该
It was unfair of me to ask you to stay on the bench.
如果你想退休  就可以退休
If you want to retire, you should.
感谢您的考虑  总统先生
I appreciate your consideration, Mr. President.
我认为我首先该做的
Well, I thought the first thing I should do
就是找到一名合适的继任者
is to find a suitable successor.
一个你会认可  能让你放心的人
Someone you would approve of to put your mind at ease,
我想我找到了
and I think I've found one.
是谁
Who?
希瑟·邓巴
Heather Dunbar.
我觉得她会是位很棒的法官
I think she'd be an excellent justice.
很高兴你同意选她
I'm glad you agree.
只是没想到会选她  毕竟她...
Just an unlikely choice, given how vociferous she--
在沃克调查中咄咄逼人  是的
With the Walker investigation, yes.
但那只会增加我对她的尊重
But that only increases my estimation of her.
她很有责任感
She has a great sense of duty.
比我共事过的任何副检察长都有责任心
More than any Solicitor General I've ever worked with.
真希望我早能知道您找我来的原因
I wish I'd known the reason you invited me beforehand.
就可以免去这趟麻烦了
I could have saved you the trouble.
为什么呢
Why?
我几个月前跟您聊过之后
After I talked to you a couple of months ago,
露丝说您是给了我一份礼物
Ruth said you'd given me a gift.
如果我不当法官  会很痛苦
That I would be miserable if I weren't on the bench.
她跟我儿子都谈了  他们也同意
She talked to my sons and they all agreed.
只要我的健康还允许
As long as I'm well enough to serve the court,
我就想继续做下去
that's where I want to be.
我们留意着点2016的走势
And we'll keep an eye on 2016.
如果共和党看上去能赢  我就辞职
If it looks as though the Republicans will win, I'll step down.
如果不会  我就留下  但不用着急
If not, I'll stay. But, there's no rush.
我非得毁掉这个人吗
Must I destroy this man?
总统先生
Mr. President?
不  我不想
No. I won't.
您说什么
Excuse me?
我不能袖手旁观
I won't stand by
看你做这个错误的决定
and watch you make this mistake.
我已经考虑好了
I've thought this through.
我们不是朋友  罗伯特
We're not friends, Robert.
我们没那么熟
We don't know each other that well.
但我关心你
But I care about you.
因为你在法院服务了超过20年
Because you served for more than 20 years on the bench.
你裁定的判例存世会比你我都长久
You've established legal precedents that will outlive both of us.
而且...
And...
昨天的事你也许可以用人老糊涂解释过去
maybe you can explain away yesterday as a senior moment.
但要是再出现你没法解释的其他状况呢
But what if another moment happens that you can't explain away?
万一你患病的消息泄露出去了呢
What if somehow the news of your illness leaks?
那你写下的每个判决都会受人怀疑
Then every decision you've written will be called into question.
都将受到质疑
They'll be challenged.
你一生的成果瞬间就会化为乌有
And a life's work will be undone in a heartbeat.
您有什么其他心思吗
Do you have some ulterior motive here?
只是为你着想
Only your best interests.
那为什么要这么急
But why the urgency?
我想保护你
I want to protect you.
大法官  我在请求你  在恳求你
Justice, I'm asking you, I'm pleading with you.
别让事情脱离你的掌控
Don't let events get out of your control.
你能重新考虑吗
Will you reconsider?
谢谢您的关心  总统先生
I appreciate your concern, Mr. President.
我再跟露丝商量一下  给您答复
Let me speak again to Ruth and I'll get back to you.
谢谢你  大法官
Thank you, Justice.
你这是禁言
It's a moratorium.
我们不那么叫
We're not calling it that.
随你们叫什么  但没人开口
Call it whatever you want, nobody's talking.
我们在避免发布错误信息
We're trying to prevent misinformation.
我本想写《美就法》的报道
I'm supposed to write about AmWorks.
但行政部门都
How can I do that  when no one
没人跟我说话我该怎么写
from the executive branch will speak to me?
国会那边情况瞬息万变
This thing's shifting under our feet in Congress.
等我写完早简报  已经成了昨日黄花
By the time I finish the morning brief, it's already outdated.
我不是要求跟总统一对一对话  但...
I'm not asking for a one-on-one with the president, but...
但劳工部长  财政部长
the Secretary of Labor, Treasury,
他的哪个经济顾问都行
one of his economic advisors.
给你特殊待遇吗
Give you special treatment?
我觉得你们下令禁言是因为你们要输
I think you issued the moratorium because you're losing the battle.
事关五千亿美金
It's 500 billion dollars.
这是罗斯福新政以来最大的就业计划
This is the largest jobs program since the New Deal.
当然是场激战  但那不代表我们失利
Of course it's a slugfest. That doesn't mean we're losing.
那让我跟能确证那点的人谈谈
Then let me speak to someone who can confirm that.
因为我从共和党人那里听到的
Because all I'm hearing from the Republicans is that
都是《美就法》绝对不会通过
AmWorks will never see the light of day.
我很同情你  艾拉
I sympathize with you, Ayla.
我也希望能让你如愿
I wish I could give you what you want.
总统要我们过去
The president needs us.
我们迟点再聊
So we'll talk later.
迈克尔·科里根  上周国宴时
Michael Corrigan, the activist who organized the protest
组织抗议的激进分子
at the state dinner last month,
三小时前在莫斯科被俄国警方逮捕
arrested by Russian police three hours ago in Moscow.
视频已经疯传
The video is going viral.
他是国内外知名的同性恋权利活动家
He's a high profile gay rights activist, nationally and abroad.
过去六周以来他一直在俄罗斯高调活动
And he's been very vocal in Russia over the last six weeks.
这是联调局关于他的档案  先生
Here's the bureau file on him, sir.
我们跟克里姆林宫接触了吗
Have we been in touch with the Kremlin?
杜兰特国务卿现在正在丹吉尔[摩洛哥城市]
Secretary Durant is in Tangier right now.
我打电话知会了她  她也联系了布加耶夫
I briefed her by phone and she reached out to Bugayev.
但他们还没有联系上
But they have not connected yet.
格莱姆斯大使也在莫斯科上下疏通
Ambassador Grimes is making calls in Moscow,
但目前没有进展
but nobody's engaging,
只知道他们打算提出严重的指控
other than to say they plan on fully prosecuting him.
大使  你认为这会不会是对你在联合国
Ambassador, do you think this could be in retaliation
活动的报复行为
for what you're doing at the UN?
有这个可能
It could be.
俄罗斯人对这个决议案非常不满
The Russians are very upset about this resolution.
我去莫里科夫那里探探口风
I'll see what I can find out from Moryakov.
把新闻发布会推迟到明天
Let's hold off on the press conference until tomorrow.
我希望能汇报些好消息  而不是两手空空
I'd like to deliver some good news instead of no news.
同时
In the meantime,
发一个声明  说我们正在接触莫斯科方面
put out a statement that we're in communication with Moscow.
我们正竭尽所能
And that we're doing everything we can
把科里根先生营救回美国  谢谢各位
to get Mr. Corrigan back to the United States. Thank you all.
我个人也讨厌这套法律
Personally, I hate the law.
古板又恐同的玩意
It's medieval homophobic nonsense.
但法律就是法律
But it's the law.
我们刚刚谈过
I don't think it's coincidence
科里根就被逮捕了  我不觉得是巧合
that Corrigan was arrested after our conversation.
我也不觉得是巧合
Well, I wouldn't think it was a coincidence either.
那你有什么期望
So what do you hope to achieve?
我的期望和你一样  让科里根先生获释
The same thing as you do: Mr. Corrigan's release.
前提是我撤回决议案
If I withdraw the resolution.
我认为莫斯科肯定会将此举视为善意的表示
I think Moscow would certainly see it as a sign of goodwill.
我们可不会为了表示善意
Well, we don't barter goodwill
就拿美国公民的自由做交易
for the freedom of American citizens.
我提议过将他立即驱逐出境
I actually advocated for his immediate deportation.
我也认为把他扔进大牢只能适得其反
I agree that tossing him in jail is counterproductive,
但高层心意已决
but my superiors are adamant.
帮佩特罗夫看清局势吧
Save Petrov from himself.
我可没资格质疑他
It's not my place to question him.
和你不同  我毕竟没嫁给总统
Unlike you, I'm not married to my boss.
我会把克里姆林宫的立场转达给总统
I'll relay the Kremlin's position to the president.
如果我们让步  约旦河谷计划就搁浅了
If we give in, the Jordan Valley plan is over
还让俄罗斯人觉得他们可以漫天要价
and we show the Russians we can be blackmailed.
难道我们眼睁睁让科里根坐穿牢底吗
So we're just supposed to let Corrigan rot away?
我想如果我们在联合国保持强硬立场
I think if we continue to drive hard at the UN,
我们就会有更多筹码
we'll gain leverage.
凯茜怎么想
What does Cathy think?
她也同意
She agrees.
只要科里根一天没放出来  我就得挨一天骂
I'm gonna take flak every day that Corrigan remains in jail.
如果你退步的话就会被骂死
And you'll take more if you back down.
但这样一来我就得在新闻发布会上
But it does mean I have to get in front of the press
两手空空地面对媒体
with absolutely nothing of substance to say.
你在国会混了20年  没话找话你最拿手
You spent 20 years in Congress. You're good at that.
听到你笑真好
It's good to hear you laugh.
睡一会儿吧  我明天再打给你
Get some sleep. I'll call you tomorrow.
晚安
Good night.
具体是谁负责华盛顿和莫斯科之间的沟通
Who specifically is communicating between Washington and Moscow?
两国之间的联络是由国务院
All of our communication is between the State Department
和俄罗斯外交部负责的  艾拉
and the Russian Foreign Ministry. Ayla.
您在声明中一直称这是侵犯言论自由
In your statement, you persisted in calling this a free speech issue,
但同性恋权利难道不也是主题吗
but isn't gay rights really at the center of this?
科里根先生是因为自由发表意见被捕的
Well, Mr. Corrigan was arrested for speaking his mind.
无论他是持什么立场
No matter what his opinions...
您是不是在回避问题  总统先生
Aren't you skirting that, Mr. President,
因为您在同性恋权利问题上立场含混不清
because your stance on gay rights is unclear?
现在清楚无疑的是科里根先生的被捕不公正
What is clear is that Mr. Corrigan's detainment is unjust
而如我所言  我们正动用一切手段
and, as I said, we're doing everything we can
确保他安全回家  扎克利
to make sure that he can come home. Yes, Zachary.
我还没问完
Following up.
如果您不参选  那么回避同性恋问题
Isn't dodging gay rights a calculated move
是不是太过算计了
for a man not running for office?
你说我在回避问题
You think I'm dodging?
那我今天就把话跟你说清楚
Well, then let me be as clear as I possibly can be.
同性恋群体是有权利的
Gay people have rights.
而本届政府始终坚信
And this administration has always believed
科里根先生有权就任何问题
that Mr. Corrigan has the right to speak his mind
自由表达观点  而无需担心被捕
without fear of being arrested on any issue,
不管是同性恋权利还是别的什么
whether it's gay rights or something else.
另一件清楚无疑的事
And what is also quite clear
就是你在礼仪课上肯定没好好听讲
is that you must have failed etiquette class.
扎克利
Yes, Zachary.
-总统先生  -您为什么不接见约翰·帕斯特纳克
- Mr. Prisident-- - Why won't you speak to John Pasternak,
-迈克尔·科里根的丈夫  -萨伊德女士
- Michael Corrigan's husband? - Ms. Sayyad,
今天到场的还有其他记者和媒体
there are other members of the press here today,
帕斯特纳克先生一直在试图联系白宫
Mr. Pasternak has been trying to contact the White House
但却没人理他
and no one will speak with him.
实在抱歉各位  我还有会
I do apologize, I have a meeting.
真希望能回答你们所有人的问题
I wish I could've gotten to all your questions.
还有任何疑问的话
But if you have any further inquiries,
请问格雷森先生  非常感谢
please direct them to Mr. Grayson. Thank you very much.
抱歉  先生
I apologize, sir.
你太过分了
You went too far.
那是我的工作
I did my job.
这是有规则的  要顾及礼仪
There's protocol. There's basic decorum.
那这样  你为我解除《美就法》的禁言
How about this: you lift the moratorium for me on AmWorks,
我消失五周  专心酝酿长文
I disappear for five weeks. Focus on my long-lead piece.
科里根和其他事我都不碰
I don't touch Corrigan or anything else.
你就指望我来警告你
You wanted me to chew you out.
如果能让你开口的话
If that's what it takes to get us talking.
所以我要收回你的白宫记者证
Which is why I need your credential.
-什么  -你的白宫记者证
- What? - Your credential.
-你开玩笑吧  -我笑了吗
- You're kidding. - Do you see me laughing?
你无权收回我的白宫记者证
You don't control my credential.
白宫记者协会才有权
The Correspondents' Association does.
我刚跟乔尔·维曼聊过
And I just spoke to Joel Weinmann.
他不会的
He wouldn't.
你成功了  艾拉
You succeeded, Ayla.
我要为所有
I'm lifting the moratorium
其他记者解除《美就法》的禁言
for every other member of the press corps.
代价是你的白宫记者证
The price was your credential.
他没有理由
He has no grounds.
你对总统不敬
You disrespected the president,
对政府不敬  更对你的同行们不敬
the office, and most importantly, your fellow colleagues.
根本不难说服他
It wasn't a tough sell.
那我下一篇报道就写这个
Then this becomes my next story.
迫害记者  上下勾结  尽职却付出代价
Punishing a member of the press. Collusion. Pay for play.
我会否认
And I'll deny.
而且你觉得记者协会主席
And do you think the head of the association
会承认吗
is gonna admit anything?
艾拉  你两边都没有盟友了
You don't have any friends, Ayla, on either side of the fence.
总统刚就言论自由发表了声明
The president just made a statement about free speech.
你就要把记者踢出白宫吗
Now you're gonna start kicking reporters out of the White House?
-不  只踢你  -不只是我
- No. Just you. - No, not just me!
你惹上了全美第二大日报
You're fucking with the second largest daily in America.
你能甩掉我
You can get rid of me,
但甩不掉我工作的报社
but you can't get rid of the institution I work for.
说完了吗
You done?
别一时得权就昏了头  赛斯
Don't let your 15 minutes of power go to your head, Seth.
封壳你留着做纪念吧
You can keep the plastic if you want... as a souvenir.
反正也只能作纪念了
That's all it's good for, now.
你好
Hello?
嗯
Yeah.
真的吗
Are you serious?
好吧
Okay.
操
Fuck.
我有事找总统
I need to speak to the president.
我们希望通过法律完善政府
Through our laws, we seek to create a more perfect union.
滥用法律的政府官员
Government officials who abuse the law,
或者哪怕是
or, at the very least,
打法律的擦边球  借机牟利的人
exploit the edges of it for their own personal gain,
都是在玷污民主  削弱这个伟大的国家
tarnish our democracy and weaken the bonds of our great nation.
民主党必须走出丑闻的阴影
The Democratic Party must step out of the shadow of scandal
改头换面
and redefine itself.
她演完了让她来一趟
I want her here when she's done with this stunt.
迎接一个透明  真诚  正义的新时代
Embracing a new era of transparency, honesty and justice,
希瑟·邓巴
最高法院门外
这个国家需要一位曾在全美诸多法庭里
this country deserves a president who has dedicated herself
为这个理想献身的总统
to those ideals in this court and many others,
一位毕生都在捍卫法律的总统
who has spent her entire life defending the law,
一位如今想投入法律执行的总统
and who now wants to dedicate herself to enforcing it.
迎接一位正直的总统吧
Let's restore integrity to the Oval Office.
用总统的权力根除腐败  以身作则
Use its power to root out corruption and lead by example.
今天  在家人和朋友面前
Today, before my family and friends,
在上帝和美国最高法院面前
my God, and the highest court in our land,
我宣布参选
I announce my candidacy
美利坚合众国总统
for President of the United States of America.
邓巴女士此次宣布参选
There was no indication Ms. Dunbar
并没有任何先兆
had plans to run for president.
她将成为史上第二位
This will make her the second Solicitor General
参选总统的副检察长
in history to run for president,
另一位是1908年的威廉·霍华德·塔夫特
the only other being William Howard Taft in 1908.
安德伍德总统已经宣布不会...
With President Underwood declaring he will not--
-总统先生  -邓巴女士
- Mr. President. - Ms. Dunbar.
请坐吧
Please, take a seat.
我的辞呈
My letter of resignation.
我不能接受
I can't accept that.
你对我们太重要了
You're too valuable to us.
我要竞选就得离职
I can't run for office as Solicitor General.
那你该重新考虑下竞选的事
Then you should reconsider running for office.
现在已经太迟了
It's too late for that, I think.
我不理解  希瑟
I don't understand, Heather.
我给了你最高法院的位置
I offered you a seat on the Supreme Court.
前提是雅各布斯辞职  但他不会
If Jacobs was stepping down, which he isn't.
你跟他谈过
You spoke to him.
作为副检察长  我跟每位法官关系都很好
As Solicitor General, I'm friendly with all the justices.
我没有声张那些关系
I keep those relationships private
免得人怀疑法官对我有偏袒
so no one will suspect any bias toward me.
但罗伯特跟我关系很好
But Robert and I are very close.
他和露丝每月都邀我去吃顿晚饭
He and Ruth have me over for dinner once a month.
所以你早知道他患病的事了
So you already knew about the Alzheimer's?
确诊当天他就告诉我了
He told me the day he was diagnosed.
我一向是为他的利益考虑
I've never had anything but his best interests at heart.
你并不关心罗伯特
You don't care about Robert.
你只是想让我出局
You wanted to sideline me.
那么你真觉得你有机会进这间办公室
So you actually think you have a shot at this office?
是的  党内领导层也这么觉得
Yes, I do. And so does the leadership.
你是不自量力  希瑟
You're in over your head, Heather,
无论博奇和乌麦克跟你说了什么
no matter what Birch and Womack are telling you.
你在乎什么呢  总统先生
Why should it concern you, Mr. President?
你已经宣布不参加竞选了
You've announced that you're not running.
你参选有个人感情因素吗
Is this personal for you?
别自作多情了
Don't flatter yourself.
你整倒了沃克  但你打不倒我
You got Walker, but you couldn't get me.
我没必要通过竞选来把你赶走
I don't have to run to make sure you leave office.
你本来就赢不了
You couldn't win anyway.
我参选是因为我知道我能做个好总统
I'm running because I know I'd make a good president.
你很可能能当个好总统
You might very well make a good president.
但现在  你是在妄想
But right now, you're being delusional.
博奇来找我时  我还不确定
When Birch approached me, I wasn't sure.
我很动心  但也知道成功机会不大
I was tempted, but I knew it was a long shot.
你给我提名时  我完全不知所措了
And when you offered the nomination, I was overwhelmed.
那是我毕生工作的目标
It's what I'd been working toward my entire career.
但后来我跟罗伯特聊了聊
But then I spoke to Robert.
他告诉我你是怎么威胁他后
And when he told me how you threatened him,
我就知道我必须参选
I knew I had to run.
总得有人把这个办公室里的臭气洗洗干净
Someone needs to scrub the stink from this office.
我没有威胁他
I didn't threaten him.
那你管那叫什么
What would you call it?
我是想挽救他
I was trying to save him,
就像我现在也是想挽救你
in the same way I'm trying to save you now.
一旦他患病的消息泄露  这总会泄露的
Once the news of his Alzheimer's gets out, which it will,
因为无论我们怎么说谎隐瞒
because no matter how much we all try to lie about it,
它总会传出去
it's gonna leak,
你能想象那对他的名誉会造成多大影响吗
can you imagine what that's going to do to his reputation?
他不该遭此境遇
He deserves better than that.
你也该得到比陪跑更高的地位
And you deserve better than being an also-ran.
帮我说服他
Help me convince him.
接受最高法院你应得的那个职位
Take the seat on the court where you belong.
你就是这么说服自己的吗
Is this how you live with yourself?
把不堪的目的说成好听的
By rationalizing the obscene into the palatable?
我还没允许你走
I haven't excused you yet.
爱荷华初选见吧
See you in Iowa.
没有信仰
I wouldn't have made it
我是支撑不过这八个月的
through the past eight months without my faith.
但没有这个团体  我也支撑不过来
But I wouldn't have made it without this community, either.
在那些艰难的日子里...
And on tough days...
我一直提醒自己这点
I remind myself of that.
我不是一个人
That I'm not alone.
我有你们大家
That I have all of you.
我认为承认这点是很重要的
And I think it's important to acknowledge that.
还有表达感谢
To give thanks.
所以  谢谢你们
So thank you.
谢谢所有人
All of you.
谢谢你们一直都在我身边  在我心里
For always being there. For always being here.
我得走了  再见
I have to go. I'll see you soon.
我只想说一句  你刚才讲的...
I just wanted to say, what you said...
真的让我很受触动  关于团体的
it really connected with me. About community.
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
我很高兴
I'm glad.
我叫丽萨
I'm Lisa.
我叫麦克斯
Of course. Max.
你是新来的
You're new.
其实是第一次来
It was my first time, actually.
你在附近住吗
Do you live around here?
住陶森市  开车来的
Towson. Just drove up.
你怎么找到我们的
How did you find out about us?
网上
Online.
网站
Website.
我就是到处看看
Yeah, I was surfing around, and I was...
在找点东西
I was looking for something and...
-太傻了  -不会的
- It's stupid. - No. No, no.
告诉我吧
Tell me.
好吧  几个月前  一个姑娘
Okay, well, a few months ago, this girl...
其实是我一生挚爱...
the love of my life, actually...
分手了吗
Breakup?
她离开了我
She just left me.
非常突然
Out of the blue.
有一天她说结束了  就到此为止了
You know, one day she just said it was over and that was it.
是啊
Yeah.
那很痛苦
That's hard.
不久前我也经历了类似的情况
I went through something similar not that long ago.
真的吗
Oh, really?
其实就是我今晚说的
Sort of what I was talking about tonight
我经历的艰难时期
with the hard time I had been through.
发生了什么
What happened?
老故事了
Ancient history.
哪个男的离开了你吗
A guy left you?
其实是女的
It was a woman.
我想我还没有完全放下  但时间会治愈一切嘛
I guess I'm not completely over it, but time heals, you know?
我得回家了  很高兴认识你  麦克斯
I gotta get home, but it was nice to meet you, Max.
很高兴认识你  丽萨
Nice meeting you, Lisa.
能重新安排一下吗  我看看
Can we reschedule? Let me see.
嗯  能把那个提前半小时吗
Yeah, yeah. Can you move that up by a half an hour?
你好
Hello?
现在方便吗  邓巴女士
Is this a good time, Ms. Dunbar?
你是哪位
Who is this?
道格·斯坦普
Doug Stamper.
你怎么拿到这个号码的
How did you get this number?
拿到号码很简单  你应该问的是
Phone numbers are easy. What you should be asking
我怎么知道你今晚要跟吉阿罗参议员见面
is how I knew you were meeting with Senator Giallo tonight.
回头看走廊
Look down the hallway.
你们先走  我到下面找你们
Go ahead. I'll meet you down there.
好吧
All right.
别过来  待在原地
No. Stay where you are.
我们不能被别人看到在一起
We wouldn't want to be seen together.
总统派你来的吗
Did the president send you?
不是  我们不联系了
No. He and I aren't in touch.
那你为什么来这里
Then why are you here?
你要组竞选团队  我想加入
You're forming your team. I want to be a part of it.
真实原因呢
The real reason.
这就是原因
That is the reason.
他派你来的  别骗我
He sent you. Don't lie to me.
我已经九个月没参与任何事了  邓巴女士
I've been out of the game for nine months, Ms. Dunbar.
我想重回战局
I want to get back in.
你要组建竞选团队
You're forming your team,
我想成为开朝一员
and I want to get in on the ground floor.
光有领导层还不够
The leadership isn't enough.
你还需要基层人士
You need the rank and file.
他们与各市县权力掮客的关系
Their connections to county and municipal power brokers.
从初选开始到全面展开
The chiefs of a thousand kingdoms
每一场选举中的当权人物
in every primary from Iowa to Super Tuesday.
我在党鞭办公室工作了十年
I worked in the whip's office for ten years.
我手上有每个人的资料
I have files on every single member.
他们要什么  跟谁睡  中午吃什么
What they want, who they sleep with, what they eat for lunch.
我对你会很有价值
I can be valuable to you.
你怎么知道我今晚要跟吉阿罗见面
How did you know I was meeting with Giallo tonight?
你跟领导层来往密切
You rub shoulders with the leadership.
我跟为他们工作的人来往密切
I rub shoulders with the people who work for them.
考虑一下吧  邓巴女士  我只有这点请求
Think about it, Ms. Dunbar. That's all I ask.
下楼
Going down.
我犯了个错误
I made a mistake.
她在总统办公室里跟我说话的方式
I mean, the way she spoke to me in the Oval,
让我恨不得勒死她
I wanted to strangle her.
她到底在想什么
I mean, what is she thinking?
跟在职总统竞争
Running against an incumbent
我都提出给她最高法的职位了
when I offered her a seat on the court--
博奇向她吹耳边风时  她就决定要参选了
She was going to run the moment Birch whispered in her ear.
人一旦开始想象自己坐在总统办公室里
Once people imagine themselves in the Oval,
就不会再回头了
there's no turning back.
你跟他们一样清楚
You know that as well as anybody.
是我自己的错  不应该给雅各布斯留选择余地
It's my own damn fault. Shouldn't have given Jacobs the choice.
我应该在问她之前就宣布提名
I should've just announced her nomination before I even asked her.
-需要我回家吗  -不用
- Should I come home? - No.
我只需要考虑一下  理清思路
I just need to think. I need to clear my head.
我能做点什么
Tell me what I can do.
我为什么要有所保留
Why did I hold back?
我为什么要对雅各布斯留情
Why did I show Jacobs any mercy?
弗兰西斯  这可不像你的作风
Francis, this doesn't sound like you.
把这些抛在脑后  想想下一步怎么做
Put this behind you. Think about what's next.
是因为默罕默德
It was because of Mahmoud.
我让他影响了我
I let him get to me.
那些士兵灵柩上的国旗
And all those flags on those coffins and those soldiers, whose--
我调派  又下葬了他们  是我的...
I deployed and then I buried in the ground. It's my--
别说了  这帮不上忙
Stop it. This isn't doing you any good.
你想谈的话我可以跟你谈
I will talk about this with you if you want,
但我不允许你怀疑自己
but if you're doubting yourself, I can't indulge that.
是啊  你说得对
No, you're right, of course.
明早再谈吧
Well, let's talk in the morning.
-有需要随时找我  -我知道
- I'm here if you need me. - I know.
-晚安  -晚安  弗兰西斯
- Good night. - Good night, Francis.
能帮我接艾迪斯主教吗
Yes, can you reach out to Bishop Eddis for me?
我等着
I'll hold.
谢谢  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
-让我们单独谈谈  -好的
- If we can have some privacy. - Yes, sir.
还骑博纳维尔呢
Still riding the Bonneville?
把67款卖了换了派普伯恩  那车不错
Sold the '67 for a Pipeburn. Beautiful bike.
有机会带我兜一圈
You should take me for a spin sometime.
算了吧
I don't think so.
骑那个太找死
They're a death wish.
至少你知道自己能上天堂
At least you know you have a place in heaven.
有什么事  总统先生
What's on your mind, Mr. President?
那天葬礼
The burial the other day.
你谈到了亚伯拉罕和以撒
You talked about Abraham and Isaac.
上帝献出了他唯一的儿子
God giving up his only Son.
就跟你说说
Between you and me,
我在阿灵顿总说那一套
that's the same sermon I always use at Arlington.
安葬的士兵太多
You put enough soldiers in the ground,
就懒得写新悼词了
you get tired of writing new ones.
那是我第一次听
It was the first time I had heard it.
肯定不是最后一次
Won't be the last.
我想理解正义
I want to understand what justice is.
这可不简单
That's a big one.
我知道
I know.
我们的正义是先辈创造的
There's our justice, the kind men create.
以《十诫》之类的戒律为基础
We base it on things like the Ten Commandments.
但文字总有不同的解读方法
But those can be read a million different ways.
"不可杀人"说的倒是很明确
"Thou shalt not kill" seems pretty clear.
说得轻巧  我们不杀人
Who's to say? If we didn't kill,
也许还有别人开杀戒
others would kill instead of us.
《圣经》里谈了许多杀戮的故事
There's a lot of killing in the Bible.
大卫王就是位勇士
King David was a warrior.
那怎么用上帝给摩西的《十诫》解释他的行为呢
How do you reconcile that with the laws that God gave Moses?
《十诫》也可以有不同解读
Even those laws require interpretation.
有两条一定要记牢
There are two laws we have to remember above all else.
他要我们爱上帝
He tells us to love God
还要互敬互爱
and to love each other.
怎么去爱你杀的人
You can't love the people you kill.
当然可以
You sure as hell can.
想杀你的人  你也要去爱
And you have to love the people who are trying to kill you.
耶稣也爱罗马人
Jesus loved the Romans.
他说  "天父  原谅他们吧
"Father, forgive them," He said,
他们并不清楚自己的所作所为"
"For they know not what they do."
他为什么不反抗
Why didn't he fight?
他为什么自愿牺牲
Why did he allow himself to be sacrificed?
我自问过许多遍
I ask myself that question a lot.
我理解《旧约》的上帝
I understand the Old Testament God,
权力至高无上
whose power is absolute,
用恐惧统治人类  但是他...
who rules through fear, but... him.
人类无法拥有至高无上的权力
There's no such thing as absolute power for us,
只能接受上帝的统治
except on the receiving end.
用恐惧统治不会有好下场
Using fear will get you nowhere.
你的工作不是裁决正义
It's not your job to determine what's just.
你也无权决定喜欢哪个上帝
It's not your place to choose the version of God you like best.
你不必一个人效忠国家
It's not your duty to serve this country alone,
也最好不要只想着为自己牟利
and it better not be your goal to simply serve yourself.
你效忠主
You serve the Lord.
通过他效忠众生
And through Him, you serve others.
两条规则
Two rules.
爱上帝  互敬互爱
Love God. Love each other.
就这样
Period.
你不是救世主  总统先生
You weren't chosen, Mr. President.
他才是
Only he was.
我能单独待一会儿吗
May I have a few moments?
一个人待着  祈祷
For myself. To pray.
可以啊
It's all yours.
爱
Love?
你就想推销这个吗
That's what you're selling?
我不要
Well, I don't buy it.
没事吧  先生
Is everything all right, sir?
我在祈祷  他突然倒了
I was praying and it just fell.
找个人清理一下
Please have someone clean this up.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
这下我有上帝的耳朵了[上帝肯听我的了]
Well, I've got God's ear now.
奥巴马2008年大选期间对小布什的反恐政策有很多批评
但当选总统后  他在国家安全和反恐政策上
并没有完全放弃小布什政府在反恐事务中的鹰派主张
虽然奥巴马下令美军和情报机构
不许再对被俘的恐怖嫌犯进行"水刑"等逼供措施
但同时也下令扩大在中东地区进行无人机"定点打击"的军事行为
在过去几年中  无人机轰炸
成为奥巴马清除中东恐怖嫌犯的主要手段
这个政策在美国国内招致来自民主党左派
和共和党自由意志派人士的广泛反对
一些民间人权组织不断出版报告称美军行为造成大量无辜民众伤亡
2013年3月  美国司法部长霍德发表声明称
在未经适当司法程序前提下  在美国境内使用无人机
对美国籍恐怖嫌犯进行打击是违宪的
但是霍德没有说在境外进行无人机打击是违宪行为
司法部长霍德的声明发表后  来自肯塔基州的共和党参议员
著名的自由意志派政客兰德·保罗
在国会进行了长达13个小时的马拉松式演讲
其主题就是抗议美军出动无人机定点消灭美国籍的恐怖分子
他认为无论在国内还是国外
未经司法程序针对美国公民的无人机打击都是违宪的